Ramakant Maroti Barade

E-mail: ramakantb2@gmail.com

Contact No: 9970707312

Address: Flat No.16 Gitai Apartment phase-1 Dighi Road, Bhosari, Pune.

Designation: Mechanical CAD Design Engineer

Profile Summary

Mechanical engineer with 6 years of industrial experience, (i.e., 4.7 years in design & 1.3 years in Quality engineer. Providing technical design direction on mechanical products, machine parts, and components for global ISO manufactures, Proficient in creating detailed mechanical drawings for piece parts and assemblies & sheet metal design & drafting with ASME Y14.5/ISO 1101 standards for engineering drawing using Creo5.0/ Pro-E /Catia V5 Software.

***** JOB DESCRIPTION:

- Hands on experience with 3D modeling and 2D drafting/detailing/assembly modeling of mechanical components using Pro-E/Creo5.0/ Catia V5 software.
- Good understanding of Geometric Dimensioning and Tolerancing (GD&T) as per Required standard (ASME Y14.5 / ISO1101) and tolerance stack-up calculation.
- Good understanding of Manufacturing Process such as Sheet metal, casting, Forging, stamping, machining and welding process.
- Effective use of sheet metal Part design guide to create/ modify design concepts.
- Prepare design presentation & review to improve product performance and resolve technical issues.
- Good understanding of Engine fundamentals/drive line/Axle/ Steel Wheel rim design concepts.
- Evaluate & developed concepts using design for Manufacturing & assembly Techniques (DFMA).
- Good knowledge of CAD data management Policies and design change process using windchill.
- Ability to understand customer requirements, perform basic design calculations, create design concepts/packaging layouts.
- Plan and organize daily assignments to optimize individual performance and results.
- Understanding of Materials & material management, heat treatment process & prepare BOM for manufacturing Process.
- Knowledge of Quality Management system likes IATF16949, iso-14001 & 5s.

Sr.No.	Computer Skills	Core Competencies
1	MS office	PRO-E/PTC CREO, Catia V5, NX (Unigraphics), Auto-CAD
2	MS Excel	Seven Quality Control tools (7QC)
3	Power point	Statistical Process Control (SPC)
4	Outlook Proficiency	Measurement system analysis (MSA)
5		Failure Mode & Effect Analysis (FMEA)
6		Geometric Dimensioning & Tolerance (GD &T)

Professional Experience

Kalyani Maxion Wheels Pvt. Ltd. Pune.

(April 2021 to Till Date)

Company Profile: Car, Truck Steel Wheelsand volvo bus body manufacturing. **Product:** Alloy wheels, Drop center wheels, TBS Wheels Volvo bus body structure.

Job Type: 3rd Party contract Type Through Nakshatra Laser Solution.

Position: Junior Design Engineer.

Job Responsibilities: -

Prepare 2D/3D drawing and detail drafting drawing in CREO software.

- Prepare Bill of materials and design calculation as per customer specification.
- Reviews Client's technical documentation and requirements.
- Maintains project technical files.
- Controls subcontracted discipline engineering documents.
- Sets up and executes assigned engineering activities such as detail design, verification and studies relevant to any engineering topic associated to Discipline, pursuing objectives of sound engineering and design optimization in term of costs, fabrication simplicity and safety.
- Generation of BOM, detailing & drafting to meet all the requirements of customer.
- Continuous interaction with customer to solve issues for continuous improvement.
- Recording and maintaining relevant documents to ensure smooth flow of information.

Vitesco Technologies India Pvt. Ltd. Pune .

(DEC. 2019 to March 2021)

Company Profile: Automobile Components Manufacturing.

Product: 2 wheeler & 4 wheeler fuel pump & its pars manufacturing

Job Type: 3rd Party contract Type Through Shree Sai Services.

Position: Ouality Engineer.

Job Responsibilities: -

- Monitor and control Process Quality.
- Ensure That Quality specification and SOPs are followed to ensure consistence in the process.
- To coordinate and resolve the Quality issues, initiate necessary corrective activities.
- Coordinate line inspection activities like Initial sample testing and prepare initial test Report,
- Perform X -ray test for shouldering DLA jobs. Perform destructive test for ultrasonic welded part, Leak test for M4A jobs.
- Participate in development of Quality Assurance related activities for internal process such as quality documentation.
- To provide technical support to operation.
- Analyze and improve the process quality performance.
- Perform Pre dispatch inspection & Prepare PDI reports.
- Perform GV test for Rotor, axial play measurement test, compression & tension test for ultrasonic welded part, and visual inspection test for soldering & plastic molding part using Visual measuring machine.

Western Enviro Solution Pune.

(JUN. 2015 to DES. 2019)

Company Profile: Water Treatment & SPM Machine Manufacturing. **Job Type:** on roll Position Through western Enviro Solutions Pimpri Pune.

Position: Project Design Engineer.

Job Responsibilities: -

- To design 2d,3d drawing, drafting and assembly drawing with GD&T Symbols.
- To Prepare Process flow and Instrumentation diagram (P &ID) of plant.
- To draw a plant layout and Equipment location layout drawing.
- To design Fabrication drawing of tank & Pressure vessels.
- To draw detail piping layout and Piping isometric drawing with pipe support rack design & cable tray layout drawing.
- Preparation of Technical data sheet of Equipment & Bill of material of machine parts

Academic Qualifications: -

Qualification	Name of Institute	Board/ University	Year of Passing	Aggregate %
B.E. Mechanical	Jawaharlal Nehru Engineering College Aurangabad	Dr. Babasaheb Ambedkar Marathwada University	2014	61.26%
H.S.C.	J. J. college Of Naigaon	Latur Board	2006	74.00%
Agriculture Diploma	Krishi Vidyalaya Nanded	Marathwada Krushi Vidyapith Parbhani	2004	70.41 %
S.S.C.	J. J. college Of Naigaon	Latur Board	2002	73.73 %

PERSONAL DETAILS:

Languages Known : English, Hindi, Marathi.

Marital Status : Unmarried.

Date of Birth : 09/10/1986

Correspondence Address: Flat no.16, Gitai Apt, Dighi Rd. Bhosari Pune.

Permanent Address : Gajanan Nagar Naigaon, Tq. Naigaon Dist Nanded 431709.

Declaration:

I hereby declare that all the details furnished here are true to the best of my knowledge.

Date: 26/06/2023 RAMAKANT M. BARADE

Place: Pune.